<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Framzn Hugo</title>
    <link>https://talshachar.github.io/framzn/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Framzn Hugo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://talshachar.github.io/framzn/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Safely Practice Your Draw</title>
      <link>https://talshachar.github.io/framzn/blog/how-to-safely-practice-your-draw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://talshachar.github.io/framzn/blog/how-to-safely-practice-your-draw/</guid>
      <description>Dry-fire practice is an effective way to refine your draw technique, but safety should always come first. Start by unloading your firearm completely and removing all ammunition from the room. Use a safe backstop in case of a negligent discharge.&#xA;Work through your draw slowly, focusing on consistent hand placement and smooth movement. Over time, increase speed while maintaining control. Regular, mindful practice helps build confidence and ensures you can react quickly under stress.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Trigger Protection</title>
      <link>https://talshachar.github.io/framzn/blog/the-importance-of-trigger-protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://talshachar.github.io/framzn/blog/the-importance-of-trigger-protection/</guid>
      <description>A well-designed holster completely covers the trigger guard, preventing accidental discharge while carrying or reholstering. Avoid flimsy cloth holsters that can collapse and touch the trigger.&#xA;Before holstering, make sure nothing—such as drawstrings or loose clothing—can get between the holster and trigger. Good trigger protection allows you to carry confidently and safely in daily life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summer Concealed Carry Solutions</title>
      <link>https://talshachar.github.io/framzn/blog/summer-concealed-carry-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://talshachar.github.io/framzn/blog/summer-concealed-carry-solutions/</guid>
      <description>Hot weather makes concealed carry challenging, but the right gear can help. Look for breathable holsters with sweat guards to protect both you and your firearm. Lightweight cover garments such as untucked button-down shirts offer good concealment without trapping heat.&#xA;If you find waist carry uncomfortable in the heat, consider alternative methods like pocket carry in a proper pocket holster. Whatever you choose, ensure the trigger remains fully covered for safety.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pros and Cons of Appendix Carry</title>
      <link>https://talshachar.github.io/framzn/blog/pros-and-cons-of-appendix-carry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://talshachar.github.io/framzn/blog/pros-and-cons-of-appendix-carry/</guid>
      <description>Appendix carry positions the firearm up front, typically between the 12 and 1 o&amp;rsquo;clock positions. The advantages include a faster draw and better concealment for some body types. It&amp;rsquo;s also easier to keep an eye on your firearm in crowded areas.&#xA;However, appendix carry can be uncomfortable while sitting and may present safety concerns if the trigger is not adequately covered. Always use a holster with full trigger protection and practice proper draw techniques to minimize risk.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Holster Compatibility: What Fits Your Handgun</title>
      <link>https://talshachar.github.io/framzn/blog/holster-compatibility-what-fits-your-handgun/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://talshachar.github.io/framzn/blog/holster-compatibility-what-fits-your-handgun/</guid>
      <description>Before purchasing a tuckable holster, verify that it&amp;rsquo;s molded specifically for your handgun model. A proper fit covers the trigger guard completely and holds the firearm without excessive play.&#xA;Some holster manufacturers offer shells that accommodate multiple models with similar frames. When in doubt, consult the manufacturer&amp;rsquo;s fit chart or contact their support team. A holster that fits well is crucial for safe carry and reliable retention.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comfort Tips for All-Day Concealed Carry</title>
      <link>https://talshachar.github.io/framzn/blog/comfort-tips-for-all-day-concealed-carry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://talshachar.github.io/framzn/blog/comfort-tips-for-all-day-concealed-carry/</guid>
      <description>Carrying for long hours can be uncomfortable if your holster digs into your side or shifts around. Choose a holster with smooth edges and, if possible, a sweat guard to keep moisture away from your firearm.&#xA;Adjust your belt so the holster is snug but not overly tight. Consider wearing an undershirt to create a barrier between the holster and your skin. Rotating your carry position slightly from time to time can also alleviate hot spots throughout the day.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adjusting Cant and Retention on Tuckable Holsters</title>
      <link>https://talshachar.github.io/framzn/blog/adjusting-cant-and-retention-on-tuckable-holsters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://talshachar.github.io/framzn/blog/adjusting-cant-and-retention-on-tuckable-holsters/</guid>
      <description>Most tuckable holsters allow adjustments to cant and retention so you can personalize how the gun sits and how tightly it holds. To adjust cant, loosen the screws holding the clip and rotate the holster to your preferred angle, then retighten.&#xA;Retention screws control how tightly the holster clamps the firearm. Turn them in small increments until you feel a secure hold that still allows a clean draw. Spend time experimenting at home to find the setup that feels natural and keeps your firearm secure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maintaining Your Kydex Holster</title>
      <link>https://talshachar.github.io/framzn/blog/maintaining-your-kydex-holster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://talshachar.github.io/framzn/blog/maintaining-your-kydex-holster/</guid>
      <description>Kydex holsters are durable, but they still require occasional maintenance. Wipe down the surfaces with a damp cloth to remove sweat and debris. Avoid leaving the holster in extreme heat, which can warp the material.&#xA;Check your hardware—screws and clips can loosen over time. Apply a small amount of thread locker if necessary. By keeping your Kydex holster clean and properly adjusted, you&amp;rsquo;ll ensure consistent retention and smooth draws.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Choosing the Right Belt Clip for Your IWB Holster</title>
      <link>https://talshachar.github.io/framzn/blog/choosing-the-right-belt-clip-for-your-iwb-holster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://talshachar.github.io/framzn/blog/choosing-the-right-belt-clip-for-your-iwb-holster/</guid>
      <description>Belt clips come in a variety of materials and shapes, each affecting how securely your holster attaches and how well it stays hidden. Steel clips are strong but can be bulky, while polymer clips are lightweight and less prone to scratching your belt.&#xA;Look for clips that match the width of your belt and offer enough tension to keep the holster in place during vigorous movement. Some holsters also offer soft loops for extra security.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Conceal Carry with a Tucked Shirt</title>
      <link>https://talshachar.github.io/framzn/blog/how-to-conceal-carry-with-a-tucked-shirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://talshachar.github.io/framzn/blog/how-to-conceal-carry-with-a-tucked-shirt/</guid>
      <description>Concealed carry with a tucked shirt is all about minimizing printing and keeping your draw accessible. Start with a holster specifically designed to be tuckable. Wear a sturdy belt, and place the clips as far apart as comfortable to reduce movement.&#xA;Practice your draw slowly at first, focusing on sweeping the shirt up and establishing a solid grip on your firearm. With repetition, the motion will feel natural. Remember that a loose-fitting shirt provides more room to conceal your holster and reduces the chance of printing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Best Tuckable IWB Holsters for Concealed Carry</title>
      <link>https://talshachar.github.io/framzn/blog/5-best-tuckable-iwb-holsters-for-concealed-carry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://talshachar.github.io/framzn/blog/5-best-tuckable-iwb-holsters-for-concealed-carry/</guid>
      <description>Finding the right tuckable holster can make or break your concealed carry experience. The ideal holster stays hidden under a tucked shirt while still allowing a smooth draw. Below are five well-regarded options to consider:&#xA;StealthGearUSA VG2 – ventilated and slim, perfect for hot climates. CrossBreed SuperTuck – leather backing with Kydex shell for comfort. Alien Gear Cloak Tuck 3.5 – adjustable cant and ride height. Front Line Model 38 – rigid Kydex with a sturdy tuckable clip.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>https://talshachar.github.io/framzn/blog/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://talshachar.github.io/framzn/blog/first-post/</guid>
      <description>This is the first blog post.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
